# **AARON VONTELL**

860-805-0050 vontell@mit.edu github.com/vontell avontell.com Cambridge, MA 02139

#### **Profile**

I am a junior at Massachusetts Institute of Technology, pursuing a dual degree in Computer Science and Mathematics. I have five years of full stack software development experience with personal projects, an internship, and startups.

Key Areas: Android, Java, Ul Design, AngularJS, FOSS, Agile, Project Management

#### **Work Experience**

Battlecode Competition, MIT — 2016 - Present

I am one of about ten developers who manage, create, and code the inner workings of Battlecode, MITs most popular coding competition with thousands of players and \$50,000+ of prizes. Played as a contestant in 2015, and recruited as a developer of the game in 2016. Duties include creating the yearly game in Java, managing / developing websites, and using creativity to plan the yearly game. See more at <a href="http://www.battlecode.org/">http://www.battlecode.org/</a>

Full Stack Developer, Cigna; Bloomfield, CT — Summer 2014 - 2016

Duties included conducting proof of concepts using platforms and languages such as Android, the Spring Framework, AngularJS, PL/SQL, Python, HTML5, and CSS3 (along with Bootstrap). Development also included working with teams of sizes 3 - 20 people, with daily regrouping while using the Agile development lifecycle.

Startup and Contractual Work, Multiple Companies — 2014 - Present

I am the Chief Technology office for college application guidance platform *UpStudent*, was the Lead Developer on crowd-sourced parking application *Parcio*, and was Lead Mobile Developer for startup *CarSwipe*. I also undertook Android development with concrete company *Sysdyne*. Work included building Android and web applications that connected to RESTful backends and had appealing UI design. *See more at http://avontell.com* 

### **Notable Projects / Code**

EasyAPI, IndicatorBinder, Mathlt - Java/Android, 2015 - Present

I have developed EasyAPI, a Java library that wraps RESTful services into useful Java objects; IndicatorBinder, an Android library that provides easy integration of indicators for paging and scrolling systems; and MathIt, an Android application that allows users to write math in LaTeX or MathML and send it through Facebook Messenger or other media platforms. See those and more at <a href="http://github.com/vontell">http://github.com/vontell</a>

#### Education

Currently enrolled in Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 2014 - present

Pursuing Computer Science Major and Mathematics Major, with a focus on Quantum Computing, Concentration in Science, Technology, and Society

## **Technical Skills**

Java Programming (6+ years), Android Programming (Including multiple APIs) (4 years), GIT (4 years), Python (3 years), Full Stack Web Development (HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, AngularJS, Angular Material, Spring Framework, MongoDB, PostgreSQL)

Soft Skills: Project Management, Agile Development Lifecycle, Teamwork, Extensive Documenter